KAIT SYKES

Web Developer

PROFILE

I'm a developer, designer, mentor, and a really good creative thinker. I love building beautiful, compelling websites and engaging in the complex problemsolving that web development and design so often requires to create a strong narrative experience for every project.

CONTACT INFORMATION

Phone: 416-333-3512

Email: sykeskaitlyn@gmail.com

Portfolio: kaitsykes.com

SKILLS

- ReactJS
- Node.js
- Drupal
- WordPress
- PHP
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- HTML & CSS (Sass)
- Git

- Gulp
- Sketch
- Adobe CC (InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, XD)
- Express
- MongoDB + Mongoose
- Google Analytics

EDUCATION

Juno College

Full-Stack Masterclass, 2018 Web Development Immersive, 2017

Trent University

Honours Master of Arts in Public Texts, 2014-2015

Western University

Honours Bachelor of Arts in English Language and Literature, 2010-2014

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ITS Senior Specialist (Web and Mobile Development)

Toronto Public Library, Nov 2021 - present

- Build compelling web + mobile digital products, from architecture and design through development to deployments and maintenance
- Provide subject matter expertise and support product roadmap planning

Part-Time Mentor for Web Development Fundamentals

Juno College, Oct 2020 - present

- Share knowledge, provide technical assistance, and answer student questions
- Troubleshoot and problem solve students' conceptual and technical difficulties
- Help create a friendly and comfortable learning environment

Digital Designer & Developer

Royal Ontario Museum, Sep 2017 - Nov 2021

- Maintain and create ROM's corporate website and related digital properties, including digital signage, e-communications, microsites and landing pages
- Propose strategic design solutions that enhance visitors' digital experiences and meet ROM needs
- Provide training for staff on CMS (Drupal), basic HTML, and accessibility; write style guides communicating best practices
- Develop content architecture and execute content audit for website redevelopment
- Create functional and design wireframes for redesign and development of ticketing website